# Soumi Sen

### **Summary**

Java Developer having 4+ years of hands on experience of development and enhancement of modules and applications in Healthcare, Commercial and Insurance domain projects. Possessing outstanding communication skills in interacting with clients and providing optimal business solutions. Seeks opportunity to play a challenging role in an environment of growth and excellence that will help me contribute to the growth of the organization as well.

#### **Professional Skills**

- Core Java. 4+ years hands on experience in Core java.
- Hands on experience in developing services using REST webservices: JAX-RS
- Hands on experience in Spring Boot and Hibernate
- Hands on knowledge in PL/SQL and Oracle DB
- Insurance and Healthcare domain knowledge
- Very strong **communication skills**, with good record of interaction with clients and end users. Quick learner and excellent team player, ability to meet deadlines and work under pressure with flexibility in all matters
- Strong hands on experience in different phases of Software Development Life cycle including Design, Implementation and Testing
- Have worked on projects with **Agile methodologies**

## **Computer Proficiency**

Technologies/ Frameworks	Proficient in Core Java, J2EE, Multithreading, PL/SQL. Good knowledge of REST web services using Jersey, Spring Boot and Hibernate.
Programming Language	Java, Basics of Web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), JSON, Basics of UNIX shell scripting
Additional Tools and IDEs	Eclipse IDE, JIRA, IBM Data Studio, Bit Bucket and Git Repositories

## **Employment History**

# **Deloitte Consulting USI DC Analyst**

Bengaluru, Karnataka

Client: Anthem

January 2020 – Present

Anthem is a leading health benefits company dedicated to improving lives and communities and making healthcare simpler. Through its affiliated companies, Anthem serves more than 108 million people, including more than 42 million within its family of health plans.

- Working on development and enhancement of the Scheme Website and integration with back-end data for a US based Healthcare project's **Provider Care Management** System.
- Design and integration of the system using the MVC design pattern and Core Java. Worked as part of a scrum team and participated in the scrum related activities.
- Have contributed in the enhancement of the system performance by abiding to proper coding standards, code reuse, and Extend application by making effective use of various design patterns.
- Have worked on fixing defects identified as part of release.

Client: Anixter

April 2019 – December 2019

The client supplies communications and security products and electrical and electronic wire and cable. The project involved implementation of sales process into Oracle CPQ Big Machines.

- Worked on Oracle Cost Pricing and Quote,2019 Tool
- Implemented the design for different configuration models.
- Knowledge on BMQL, BML and Integrated Webservices in CPQ.
- Analyzed, suggested, and made changes to the technical design of the configuration to increase the efficiency of the configuration module.
- I was given the opportunity to explore Oracle CPQ tool as an administrator. This new role, in turn, allowed me to have exposure to design and propose solutions to the security of sensitive information as well as to activities related to data migration.
- Had provided solutions to facilitate separate user groups and handled the user access related tasks as a primary point of contact.

#### **Additional Responsibilities**

- Along with timely deliveries, I have assisted my colleagues who were also new to the technology in finding solutions to technical issues with the help of JavaScript and CSS implementations in Oracle CPQ.
- Working on development of a coding platform using Spring Boot and Hibernate
- Explored Angular JS as part of the latest engagement.

#### **Tata Consultancy Services**

#### **Systems Engineer**

Bengaluru, Karnataka October 2015 – Present

- Worked as a senior team member with composite knowledge of different modules of a Pension Scheme project which includes development and maintenance of the Scheme Website and integration of back-end data.
- Design and integration of the system using JSPs, Core Java, Web services, Servlets.
  Have contributed in the enhancement of the system performance by abiding to proper
  coding standards, code reuse, and Extend application by making effective use of various
  design patterns.
- Use of webservices for the Implementation of authentication and authorization services through java servlets and after authentication service if data is captured in offline mode then synchronizing that data.
- Have proactively handled a number of production and non-production issues. Identified and resolved defects faced by customers by directly interacting with them.
- Very strong communication skills, with good record of interaction with clients and end
  users. Quick learner and excellent team player, ability to meet deadlines and work under
  pressure with flexibility in all matters

## Qualification

- Bachelor's in Technology in Computer Science and Engineering from West Bengal University of Technologies with a CGPA of 8.3
- Higher Secondary Education from W.B.C.H.S.E securing 75%.
- Secondary Education from W.B.B.S.E securing 87%.

## **Trainings & Certifications Undertaken**

- Acquired certification on JEE application development training
- TCS internal certification on Servlets and JSP

- E2 Certified in Core Java: TCS internal
- Having E2 proficiency certification PL/SQL: TCS internal

## Languages

English: Fluent Hindi: Fluent Bengali: Native

### **Personal Details**

Birthday: 16<sup>th</sup> October 1992 Marital Status: Married Gender: Female Nationality: India

I hereby declare that the above written are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Bangalore

Date:

Soumi Sen.